Today I would be talking about how to tack up a horse.
So boots are important when you are going to jump your horse or just for basic protection of support.
I especially like to use boots on my horse when they have horse shoes on cause the metal of the shoes can be damaging if they trip or hit themselves on accident.
So we just have 2 basic examples of boots for horses.
These are basic splint boots and you want to make sure that putting the boot on the padded area protects the inside of the horses leg where there are there ligaments are most like to be compromise.
The way that you put the boot on is that the Velcro always comes towards the back and that is how you know you have it on the right leg.
It just comes down to the bottom of the fetlock not pasted the joint where it might interfere.
The second kind of boot is a open front boot.
This protects not only the sides but the back of the horses leg and the fitting is very similar.
Once again it is important that the Velcro is pulling towards the back.
Place the cup behind the horses leg, come to the front and then the Velcro pulls towards the back.